我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
But secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
但当我女儿从未来时空前来帮忙
But when my daughter came back from the future to help,
她改变了现在
she changed the present,
现在我们的世界比以往更加危险
and now our world is more dangerous than ever,
我是唯一一个来得及拯救世界的人
and I'm the only one fast enough to save it.
我是闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
所以你打算怎么处理他
So what are you going to do with him?
我觉得我们最好花时间
I think our time would be better served
研究一下如何治好他
learning how to cure him.
你应该和兰姆登博士聊聊
You should really talk to Dr. Lamden.
古鲁德在对他使用精神打击
Grodd's attacking him psychically.
他被麻痹了
He's paralyzed.
人类弱爆了
Human weak.
我们能做治愈超能力者的解药
We could make a meta-human cure.
肯定有打破常规思维的事我们可以做
There's gotta be something we could do outside the box.
你不能去你的办公室
You shouldn't go to your office.
-现在不行  -为什么
- Not right now. - Why?
这发生多少次了
How many times has this happened?
五十二次
52.
假如我要阻止蝉  我不能吝惜
If I want to stop Cicada, I can't be so precious
弄脏闪电侠的手
about getting The Flash's hands dirty.
有时为达到目的  可以不择手段
Sometimes the ends justify the means.
我现在明白了
I get that now.
我动不了
Can't move.
闪 电 侠
第五季
第十五集
十二小时前
女士们先生们  我们终于做出了
Ladies and gentlemen, we finally have our hands
治愈超能力者的解药
on the meta-human cure.
大家都很酷  我在冻土带里待了几个星期
Cool, cool. It's not like I spent weeks
根本没什么大不了
in the frozen tundra or anything.
不不不  我觉得大家只是在等待
No, no, no. I think that just people are
这个如此重大的声明之后
waiting for the inevitable "But"
那个不可避免的"但是"
that follows such a big statement.
不  我说完了  多亏了凯特琳
Mmm, no, it's done, and thanks to Caitlin,
我们甚至有办法发射我们的特效子弹
we even have a way to deliver our silver bullet,
所以  没有"但是"
so no, no "Buts."
我相信有个很大的"但是"要来了
I believe there is a big "But" coming.
但我们得在一个超能力者身上测试解药
But we need to test the cure on a meta-human.
这就来了
There it is.
我们需要的是去拯救
What we need is to save
那些蝉在追捕的超能力者
the metas that Cicada is targeting
因为他不会停止杀害无辜的人
because he's not gonna stop killing innocent people.
-解药危险吗  -这是未经测试的血清
- Is the cure dangerous? - Well, it's an untested serum
能在细胞水平上改变生物性能
that alters biology on a cellular level,
所以在对某人试用之前
so until we try it out on someone,
我们无法知道
we have no way of knowing.
在我们开始做解药的时候
When we started working on the cure,
决定了这永远是一种选择  而不是武器
we decided that it would always be a choice, not a weapon,
所以我们需要的只是一个志愿者
so all we need is a volunteer.
真是个难题  对吧
Well, there's quite a conundrum, right?
只是需要一个超能力志愿者
A meta-human volunteer
但这个城市的超能力者
when the meta-humans in this city
要么被我们赶走  要么被蝉杀死
have been chased away by us or killed by Cicada
要么被关在铁山监狱  所以...
or incarcerated at Iron Heights Prison, so...
任何一类人都不会自愿
Nobody from either group is gonna volunteer.
不  这些罪犯不会放弃
No, these criminals are not going to relinquish
他们的超能力  但是...
their powers, although...
一定有某处的某个人愿意
There's gotta be somebody somewhere.
是的  在另一个地球上
Yes, on another Earth.
我打给哈里  看看地球二上有没有人
Oh, I'll call Harry, see if there's anybody from Earth-2
-愿意当志愿者  -就这样
-who wants to volunteer. - Yes.
我所建议的并非如此
Not really what I was suggesting.
等等  你不用找哈里了
Hold on, you don't have to call Harry.
为什么不用了
Wait, why not?
因为这里已经有一个来自地球二的超能力者
Because there's already a meta here from Earth-2,
他可能不想要自己的超能力
one who might not want his power...
尽管和他说话可能会很困难
although it might be pretty difficult to talk to him.
鲨鱼王
King Shark
你们真的认为能治好他
you really think you can cure him?
我们是这么想的
That's the idea.
莱拉  这是...
Oh, Lyla, this is, um...
我的女儿  诺拉
my daughter, Nora.
-你的女儿  -是的
- Your daughter? - Yeah.
-我来自... -我猜是未来
- I'm from-- - The future, I'm guessing.
很奇怪  是吧
Weird, right?
没有什么比某天醒来
No weirder than waking up one day
发现你的儿子曾经是女儿更奇怪的了
to find out that your son used to be your daughter.
为什么是鲨鱼王
So, why King Shark?
超能力者们的暗物质水平各不相同
Dark matter levels vary from meta-human to meta-human,
但沙伊·兰姆登是我们见过最极端的情况
but Shay Lamden's case is the most extreme we've seen,
所以我们认为如果能逆转像他这样
so we think if we could reverse the effects of a high level
高水平的突变影响
mutation like his...
就能帮助所有的超能力者
You can help all meta-humans.
我们知道鲨鱼王说话能力有限
Look, we know King Shark has limited speech,
但我们想知道是否能和他谈谈
but we're wondering, could we try and talk to him?
如果我们要这么做  需要征得他的同意
If we're gonna do this, we're gonna need his permission.
你走运了  西斯科
Well, you're in luck, Cisco.
最近他倒是挺健谈的
Lately, he's been quite talkative.
看看这些照片
Look at these pictures.
真和谐
So peaceful.
太美了
So beautiful.
-真和谐  -对吧
- So peaceful. - It is, isn't it?
我一直不明白沃利为什么去那里
You know, I never understood why Wally went there.
-现在懂了  -这令我很想知道
- Now I do. - Well, it makes me wonder.
我弟弟还会不会从西藏回来
I mean, is my baby brother ever coming back from Tibet?
我只能说比起以前
Well, all I can say is that he is more at ease
他现在更安逸自在
than he has ever been.
如果这意味着他想要远离...
And if that means he wants to stay away from...
中城这些不可思议的事
the crazy that is Central City,
那就随他吧
then, you know what? So be it.
对
Yeah.
我很高兴你回来了  老爸
Well, I am glad that you're back, Dad.
我们都很高兴你回来了
We're all glad that you're back.
就连辛格队长都很高兴你回来了
Even Captain Singh is glad that you're back.
-什... -我来
- Wha-- - I'll get it.
不不不  不行
No, no, no. No, you will not.
不行
You will not.
你已经照顾哭闹的宝宝很久了  乔·韦斯特
You have been on crying baby duty for far too long, Joe West.
真高兴你回来了
So happy you're back.
甜蜜够了
All right, all right.
我们能不能讨论一下你买的这张沙发
Are we ever gonna talk about this couch you bought?
改天吧  乔  改天吧
Another day, Joe. Another day.
可贵了
Very expensive.
但是很舒服
I mean, it's nice. Listen.
塞西尔
So, Cecile...
把最近的事都跟我说了
Has brought me up to speed.
蝉最近可没闲着啊
Cicada-- been very busy.
是啊
Yeah, well...
闪电侠小队会想出办法打败他的
You know, Team Flash will figure out a way to beat him.
但是乔西在我们眼皮底下明着帮他
But Jonesy was helping him right under our nose,
这让我想到
and that got me thinking,
蝉已经逃避追捕很久了
Cicada's eluded capture for so long
我认为
that I'm thinking that
还是有人在帮他
he's still getting help from somebody.
我要再喝点咖啡
I want more coffee.
我去多煮点咖啡
I'm gonna make some more coffee.
我给你弄一杯新鲜的
Yeah, I'll bring you a fresh cup.
一般情况下  我们不需要外界的帮助
Normally, we don't bring in outside help
但是我们听说国内顶级的鱼类学家
but we got wind that the top ichthyologist in the country
正在研究像鲨鱼王这样的案例
was doing research on cases just like King Shark's.
其实我想你们也许认识她
Actually, I think you may know her.
兰姆登博士
Dr. Lamden?
你现在替天眼会做事了吗
You're working for A.R.G.U.S. now?
难以拒绝他们  请叫我塔尼娅
Couldn't say no. And please, call me Tanya.
那鹦鹉螺实验室呢
What about Nautilus Laboratories?
麦考斯指挥官让我有机会
Director Michaels offered me the opportunity
能研究另一位沙伊·兰姆登
to work with another Shay Lamden,
他和我已故的丈夫一样
one afflicted with the same dark matter anomaly
受到同一种暗物质异常的影响
as my late husband,
但是这位沙伊的身体系统导致其神经元退化
only this Shay system was causing his neural pathways to regress.
我在教他如何有效与人沟通
I'm teaching him how to communicate effectively.
你是说他的大脑越来越接近鲨鱼的大脑了吗
Are you saying his mind is becoming more shark-like?
之前是的  但现在不是了
It was, but not anymore.
我利用一个刺激神经输出的大脑交互界面
I stopped the regression of King Shark's mind
阻止了鲨鱼王的大脑退化
using a cerebral interface that stimulates his neural outputs.
我把那叫做心电感应王冠
I call it a telepathic crown.
有点像我们做的麦德2.0
Kinda like the M.A.D. 2.0 we built.
真是令人佩服
That's brilliant.
我丈夫  就是地球一的沙伊·兰姆登
My husband, the Shay Lamden of Earth-1,
曾经是个优秀的人
was a wonderful man.
现在我有机会帮助另一个地球的沙伊·兰姆登
Now, I have the chance to help another Earth's Shay Lamden,
使他恢复人类心智
by giving him back his human mind.
虽然沙伊目前的状态
And since Shay's current state
要求他更多时间都待在水里
requires him to be in the water more,
但这些耳机能让我听到他在水下的情况
these earbuds allow me to hear him under water
他也能听到我这边
and vice versa.
心电感应王冠让塔尼娅能够接近鲨鱼王
The telepathic crown allows Tanya to get through to King Shark
并控制其暴力行为
and curb his violent behavior.
我们能用王冠和他交流吗
Can we use the crown to talk to him?
可以  但是为什么呢
Yes, but why?
我们也许能让他再次变回人类
We think we can make him human again.
我们花了不少功夫  但我们找到了办法
It's taken a lot of work, but we think we figured out a way
把暗物质聚合的细胞
to transform dark matter-infused cells
复原到非超能力状态
back to their non-meta state.
现在我们只需要测试一下
Now, all we need to do is test it,
所以我们就来找志愿者了
so we came looking for a volunteer.
这真的能行吗
That could really work?
我们能问问他吗
So, can we ask him?
沙伊  有队尖端科研实验室的人来了
Shay, a team from S.T.A.R. Labs is here.
他们可能有你想要的东西
They have something you may want--
一个能治愈你情况的超能力解药
a meta-cure for your condition.
相信我  他们初步分析的
Trust me, their preliminary analysis
扭转超能力基因变形结果
on reversing meta-gene transfigurations
证明有很大几率能起作用
proves there is a strong chance it could work,
尤其是鱼类形态上的
especially in ichthyological prospects.
不  我不是在卖弄
No, I'm not just showing off.
这是他们的研究
It's their research.
沙伊有很强的幽默感
Shay has a wonderful sense of humor.
那我们是该叫他鲨鱼王还是沙伊
So, are we supposed to call him King Shark or Shay?
是的  我还在
Yes, I'm still here. Uh-huh.
我同意
I agree.
好的
Okay.
你认为这个解药能起作用吗
You believe this cure could help?
是的
Yeah.
我们怎么开始
Where do we begin?
这里是麦考斯探员
This is Agent Michaels.
我需要所有待命士兵都到水族馆来
I need every available soldier at the aquarium now!
-爸爸  -我没事
- Dad? - I'm fine.
那反应是怎么回事  我以为他被控制住了
W-What was all that feedback? I thought he was under control.
我不知道
I don't know.
这种事之前从没发生过
Nothing like that has ever happened before.
也许他的神经退化终于到了
Maybe his neuroregression finally reached the point
王冠无法影响他的地步了
where the crown could no longer affect him.
我们可能要永远失去沙伊了
Shay could be lost forever.
不不不  原由还没搞清楚呢
No, no, no. We don't know that.
你不如和我们一起回尖端科研实验室
Why don't you come to S.T.A.R. Labs with us.
我们可以用麦德2.0增强王冠的效力
We can use the M.A.D. 2.0 to boost the crown's efficiency.
我们得赶在鲨鱼王伤害别人之前找到他
We need to find King Shark before he hurts anyone.
天眼会的后备计划已经激活
A.R.G.U.S. backup protocols have been activated,
但是鲨鱼王可能在任何地方
but King Shark could be anywhere.
我们重新设定尖端实验室的卫星
We'll re-task the S.T.A.R. Labs satellite
让其与天眼会的一同协作
to work in circuit with A.R.G.U.S.
你在想什么
What's on your mind?
只是在思考我们是否需要重新想想
Just wondering if we need to rethink
怎样去抓住他
how we're going to catch him.
别说了  那种事不可能发生
Stop, that did not happen.
确实发生了
Yes, it did. -
我的嘴唇开始麻木  然后肿胀了起来
Look, my lips went numb, and then they swelled up
情况之糟让我感觉像是做了整容手术
so bad it looked like I had plastic surgery.
-沃利做了什么  -他当然是笑了起来
- What did Wally do? - He laughed, of course.
小宝贝笑了
The baby laughed.
至少我现在知道自己对四川辣椒过敏了
At least now I know I'm allergic to Szechuan peppers.
爸爸  我今天可以留在这里工作吗
Dad, do you mind if I work here today, actually?
也许能给我们些时间叙旧
Might give us some time to catch up.
你知道我绝不会拒绝的  所以...
Well, you know I'm never gonna turn that down, so...
但是  塞西尔告诉我你有了个
Uh, but, Cecile tells me that you have
全新的豪华办公室
a fancy new office?
是啊  但是那里的下水管道系统
Yeah, yeah, it's just, you know, the plumbing
非常烂  我总不能让水
is really lousy and I can't have water
滴到我的电脑上  对吧
dripping on my laptop, right?
那个帮助我们改造客房浴室的人
Well, hey, uh, the guy that expanded our guest bath--
他活干得非常不错  而且也不贵
he did a really great job and he's really affordable.
我给你他的电话
Let me give you his number.
不了  爸爸  没事的
No, Dad, it's fine, really.
爱瑞丝  如果你不尽早处理这事
Iris, if you don't take care of this quickly,
麻烦就会越来越多
it could snowball.
这里  我给你发过去
Here. Let me just send it to you.
好吧  好的
Okay, yeah. Yeah.
说实话  这是个好主意
Actually, yeah, you know what? That's a great idea.
你发给我  然后我现在就去那边
Why don't you send it to me and I'll head over there
看看有什么能做的
and see what I can do.
-谢谢爸爸  -好吧
- Thanks, Dad. - Okay.
爱你
Love you.
爱你更多
Love you more.
所以  如果我们要增强王冠的能量
So, if we wanna boost the crown's powers,
我们需要让它与麦德2.0进行沟通
we gotta get it to talk to the M.A.D. 2.0.
用对数代码如何
What about a logarithmic code?
没错  看到没  这就是为什么
Exactly. You see, this is why we need
我们需要更多的科学家加入队伍
more scientists on the team.
沙伊总是跟我这么说
Shay tells me that all the time.
那家伙知道他在说什么
Well, the guy knows what he's talking about.
好了  那么  不如你去用
All right, so, why don't you use
我的工作台  然后我来启动这玩意
my workstation, and I'll get this going.
-很惊艳  对吧  -是啊  应该如此
- Fascinating, right? - Yeah, it should be.
这是将科技
It's the merging of technology
与人类意识结合
and human consciousness.
还有鲨鱼的  不是不是
And shark, but no, no, no.
我指的是你与沙伊·兰姆登的关系
I'm referring to your relationship with Shay Lamden.
你说的"关系"是指的什么
What do you mean, "Relationship"?
很明显啊
C'est clair.
你一提起他  你形体放松的样子
The way your posture relaxes when you're speaking of him
还有你的声音的变化...
and the way your voice modulates...
-体现出一种亲近感... -嗯
- it suggests a familiarity... - Hm.
或者是更近的关系
Or something more.
我们都是海洋生物学家  所以有很多共同点
We're both marine biologists, so we have a lot in common.
我想你可以说我们走得挺近的
I guess you could say we've grown very close.
但他只是我的患者
But he's just my patient.
当然
Oh, of course.
看看吧  我们有了突破
Look at that. We have liftoff.
它们真的在对话  看见了没有
They are actually talking. You see?
我就知道这两个疯狂的小东西能成功
I knew these two crazy kids were gonna make it work.
它们不仅仅是在同步
They aren't just synching up.
麦德2.0就像一个天线
The M.A.D. 2.0 is acting like an antennae,
把王冠的意识信号放大
amplifying the crown's psychic signal
完全超乎我的想象
beyond anything I could have imagined.
我们听到极客的欢呼了  这边的情况如何
We heard geek screaming. How are things going in here?
我只需要把头盔与我的耳机同步
I just need to synch the helmet to my earbuds,
我们就可以开始了
and we're good to go.
我把它落在表层控制室了
Left that in the Cortex,
在主控制台上  显示器的左边
in the main console, by the monitor to the left.
这样吧
You know what?
跟我来  我指给你看
Come with me. I'll show you.
-好样的西斯科  -是大家的功劳
- Great work, Cisco. - Oh, well, takes a village.
不过大家也需要个天才
But every village needs a genius
那就是我  所以嘛  谢谢
and that's me, so thank you.
现在我们只需要找到鲨鱼王然后说服他
Now we just have to find King Shark and talk him down.
不如我们把解药注射器给凯特琳
Why don't we get the cure injector to Caitlin
并确保它可以随时使用
and make sure it's ready to go.
记住  我们得先和他沟通
Well, remember, we gotta talk to him first.
对
Right.
我们发现了鲨鱼王了  他在码头
We got a hit on King Shark. He's at the wharf.
凯特琳  你确定他在那里吗
Caitlin, are you sure he's here?
他就在那
Oh, he's there.
他直冲着你过去了
He's heading straight right for you.
诺拉  该你了
Nora, you're up.
完成
Done.
系统已经同步
Okay, systems are synched.
沙伊  是我  塔尼娅
Shay? It's me, Tanya.
这些人是来想帮你的
These people are only here to help you.
请你听听他们要说的
Please listen to them.
没事的
It's okay.
我想它有效果了
I think it's working.
我觉得你说得对
I think you're right.
我们问问他...
Let's ask him--
沙伊  请你住手
Shay, stop! Please.
拜托你  我不知道他是怎么了
Please. I don't know what's wrong with him.
巴里
Barry?
伙计们  发生了什么  沙伊呢
Guys, what's happening? Where's Shay?
沙伊
Shay?
怎么了
What is it?
发生了什么
What's going on?
沙伊没事吧
Is Shay okay?
他恢复成人形了
Yeah. He's human again.
我在哪儿  你们是谁
Where am I? Who are you?
-喂  -别动  够了
- Hey, hey, hey. - No, enough!
-放开我  -没事的
- Just get off me! - It's okay.
他们都是朋友
They're friends.
塔尼娅
Tanya.
对  是我
Yeah, it's... it's me.
我是...  我吗
I'm...me?
怎么弄的
How?
我们叫它解药
We call it the cure.
是一种血清  能抑制超能力者体内的暗物质
It's a serum that suppresses dark matter in meta-humans.
你是第一个接受的人
You're the first person to take it.
只是你并没有接受
Well, except you didn't take it.
我们给你打进去的
We, um, we gave it to you.
我的头还在天旋地转呢
My--my head is still swirling around.
你们是说我又成为人类了吗
Are you saying I'm human again?
永远的吗
Forever?
差不多
Almost.
我们开发了用于超能力者人类部分的解药
We developed a cure to work on the human part of a meta-human.
而你大脑中动物的部分还有些抗拒
The animal part of your brain fought back a little bit.
你的脑下垂体中还有一些暗物质
There's still some dark matter in your pituitary gland,
但有了这个新的数据  我们应该可以
but with this new data, we should be able to
调整解药  下一剂就应该是永久性的了
address the cure and the next dose should be permanent.
兰姆登先生  我应该自我介绍一下
Monsieur Lamden, I should introduce myself.
歇洛克·威尔斯  你可能听说过我
Sherloque Wells. You've probably heard of me.
我有个问题  一直在脑子里争辩
I have a question. I've been debating in my brain.
到底是什么在主导鲨鱼王
What drives the King Shark?
是鲨鱼呢还是人呢
Is it the shark, or is it the man?
如果你问的是我是否应该
If you're asking should I be held accountable
为我的行为负责  我的回答很简单
for my actions, my answer is simple.
是  我应该负责
Yes, I should.
我不记得我伤了多少人
I don't remember how many people I hurt,
或者伤了谁  但那不是借口
or who, but that's no excuse.
你还记得什么
What do you remember?
一些片段  掠影
Fragments. Glimpses.
某一天  我还是名科学家
One day, I was a scientist.
接下来就被困在那具身体里
The next, I was trapped in that body
所有的感官体验都提升了
and everything felt heightened,
情绪就像打了激素一样
like my emotions were on steroids.
那股怒气  相当强大的愤怒
And the rage-- there was so much rage.
这说得通  当鲨鱼感受到袭击来临时
That makes sense. A shark's amygdala triggers
它的杏仁核可以激发强烈的情绪反应
a huge emotional response when it feels attacked.
也许这就是你今天逃走的原因
Perhaps that's why you escaped today.
你受到惊吓了
You were frightened.
我不知道  今天的感觉很不一样
I don't know. Today felt different.
用塔尼娅的王冠之前的事情我都记不太清
I don't remember much before I started using Tanya's crown,
但从那以后
but since then,
我的思维和记忆变得更加清晰了
my mind and memory have been much clearer.
我尤其记得你对我的好
And I especially remember the kindness that you showed me.
怎么
What--
怎么回事
What happened?
他体内的暗物质在不断复制
The dark matter in his system is replicating.
塔尼娅  对不起
Tanya, I'm sorry.
沙伊  我很抱歉  但在问题解决之前
Shay, I'm sorry, but until this is over,
我们不能让你离开尖端科研实验室
we can't let you leave S.T.A.R. Labs.
准备给他第二次注射解药的时候
Call me as soon as the cure
你第一时间联系我
is ready to inject him a second time.
我们必须知道解药是否有效
We have to know if this works.
-巴里  -什么事
- Barry? - Yeah?
你说你想让我第一时间联系你
When you said you wanted me to call you
是不是为了以便我们可以问沙伊
it was so that we could ask Shay
他是否愿意注射解药  对吗
if he wants to take the cure, right?
-凯特琳  -因为你知道
- Caitlin-- - 'Cause you know,
我们出勤的时候  你并没有给他
out in the field, you didn't really give him
其他选择
much of a choice.
但当你被鲨鱼王抓住的时候
But that was kinda hard to do
很难去做这种事
when King Shark had you dead to rights.
我们本来有办法和他沟通的
We had a way of communicating with him,
但你却不给我们机会去尝试
and you barely gave that a shot.
我们可以再试一次
And we could have tried again.
我救了你  老兄  你想要我怎么做
I saved you, man. What did you want me to do?
-拿你生命来冒险吗  -这不是重点
- Risk your life? - That's not the point.
就应该是  我们是一个团队
It should be. We're a team.
我们应该互相扶持
We're supposed to have each other's backs.
我们作为一个团队  达成了共识
And we agreed, as a team,
等待他的许可  但你根本没有这样做
to wait for his permission, but you didn't even do that.
看看现在结局怎么样
And look what happened.
你还活着
You're alive,
沙伊看起来喜欢做人类
and Shay seems to like being human,
所以这就是双赢了
so that's a win-win.
你认为这是超级英雄应该做的事情吗
Is that what you think a hero does?
强迫其他人去做你想让他们做的事情
Forces other people to do what you want them to do?
他当时正准备吃掉你  西斯科
He was gonna eat you, Cisco.
你说我该怎么办
What was I supposed to do?
我们一致同意解药不能当作武器来利用
We agreed that the cure would never be used as a weapon.
你告诉我
Tell me something.
你是临时改变的主意
Did you change your mind in the moment,
还是一直都打算这样做
or was this always part of the plan?
老爸
Dad?
我路过你的办公室
I went by your office
想找你说话
to talk to you.
老爸  我
Dad, look. I, um--
别  别说这些
Don't. Don't try it.
我听说了你们被困在疯狂的时间轮回的事
I heard about this crazy time loop you all got stuck in.
西斯科和诺拉告诉我
Cisco and Nora told me
所有版本里发生的事情
what happened in every version,
尽管我什么都不记得
and although I don't remember any of them,
单单知道发生了什么
just knowing what did happen--
你不害怕吗
You weren't scared?
我不知道
I don't know.
我闯入蝉的家
I mean, I broke into Cicada's home.
爸  我跟他对抗了
Dad, I fought him.
虽然当时很吓人
And as terrifying as that was, I mean,
但至少我可以作出反抗
at least I could react to it, you know?
但是现在  现在他知道我是谁
But now--now that he knows who I am,
我的家人是谁
who my family is,
他随时都可能会出现
I mean, he could show up at any moment.
我只是  我
I just, I--
我感觉
I feel--
无能为力
Powerless.
是的  我只是
Yeah, I just--
我不知道  我不能回去那里
I don't know, I can't go back there.
好吧  起来
Okay, get up.
老爸  我刚刚告诉过你
Dad, I just told you...
我不想回去那里了
I don't want to go back there, you know?
我不是带你回那里
I'm not taking you there.
那么去哪里
Then where?
一个我可以证明
Someplace where I can show you
你有多强大的地方
how powerful you really are.
收拾一下  快点
Pack it up. Come on.
我们得谈谈
We gotta talk.
你不知道不应该在别人
Don't you know you shouldn't
感到焦虑的时候打扰他们吗
interrupt others while they're brooding?
我正试着进入奥利弗·奎恩状态呢
Trying to get my Oliver Queen on here.
我给沙伊做了检查
I ran some more tests on Shay.
他完全不记得今早发生的事情
The reason he doesn't remember anything that happened
是因为他的大脑额叶遭受了
this morning is because he experienced a severe brain wave
严重的脑电波破坏
disruption in his frontal lobe.
这是我们都听过的反馈
That's the feedback that we all heard.
这就是他为什么像《大白鲨4:复仇》那样
So, that's why he snapped on us
攻击我们吗
like it was "Jaws: The Revenge"?
如此受损的大脑额叶当然会
A frontal lobe that compromised would of course
引发情绪和判断力的失控
result in lack of control over emotions and judgment.
你认为这也许是王冠导致的吗
So you think maybe the crown might have done this?
不  这就是关键  问题不在于王冠
No, that's the thing. The crown is not the problem.
这个装置中神经递质的传输方式
The way the neurotransmitters work in this device
绝对不会导致这种问题
never would have caused that.
所以你是说
So what you're saying is
这个心电感应王冠一直在运行
the telepathic crown was working the whole time?
是的  这就引出了一个问题
Yes, so that begs the question,
是什么让鲨鱼王变得狂暴
what caused King Shark to go berserk?
各位
Guys, hey.
我想为之前的事情道歉
I just wanted to apologize for earlier.
我确实太过分了
I was definitely too harsh.
不会吧
No way.
凯特琳
Caitlin.
你好  闪电侠
Hello, Flash.
西斯科的脑部扫描没有问题
Cisco's cerebral scan is clear.
我的也没有  我们都恢复正常了
Mine is as well. We are both back to normal.
我们不再受到控制了
No more strings on us.
冰霜杀手说她很抱歉用了冰霜攻击
Killer Frost says she's sorry for that ice blast.
那也是因为古鲁德
That was Grodd, too.
现在她准备好要反击了
Now she's ready for some payback.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
找到我们的猿猴版斯文加利的位置了吗
Do we have a 20 on our Simian Svengali?
乔治·杜·莫里耶著名小说《软帽子》中的人物
联合数据正在搜查中
Data and company are working on it,
但是古鲁德在用通灵能力隐藏自己的位置
but Grodd's psychic abilities are helping him conceal his location,
他现在可能在任何地方
so he could be anywhere by now.
我以为天眼会的每个角落都要
I thought every square inch of A.R.G.U.S.
确保二十四小时抑制超能力
was supposed to be power dampened 24 hours a day.
是这样
It is.
那么一只800磅重的大猩猩是怎样逃跑的
Then how does an 800-pound gorilla escape?
我来展示给你看吧
Let me show you.
我查看了我们的监控录像
I went through our security footage.
这是2018年3月22日晚上的录像
This is from the night of May 22nd, 2018.
-那是... -大悟之道那晚
- That's the night-- - Of the Enlightenment.
迪沃的暗物质波毁坏了周围
DeVoe's dark matter wave took down all tech
所有设备
in the surrounding areas.
幸运的是我们的发电机启动了
Luckily, our generators kicked in.
-但是用了一秒钟  -一秒钟
- But not for a second. - One second.
就足够让古鲁德用
That's all Grodd needed
精神能力向一名守卫下令
to psychically implant instructions in a guard.
指使他偷偷关掉
Instructions to secretly shut down
牢房中的超能力抑制器
the power dampeners in his cell,
并找到他需要知道的其它所有信息
and find out any other information he needed to know.
这就是为什么鲨鱼王失控了吗
So that's why King Shark flipped out?
因为古鲁德在控制他的大脑
Because Grodd was trying to mind control him?
可能只是为了分散注意力
Likely as a distraction.
古鲁德以前只控制过人类大脑
Grodd's only ever controlled human minds before.
他一定很难控制鲨鱼王
He must have had a hard time controlling King Shark
因为他的大脑中有动物部分
because of the animal part of his brain.
鲨鱼王在试图抵抗古鲁德的钢铁意志吗
So King Shark was trying to resist Grodd's iron will?
真敬佩他
Respect.
如果古鲁德在这一年里都有超能力
If Grodd's had his powers for a year,
他为什么等到现在才逃跑
why wait until now to escape?
他第一件事就是偷走心电感应王冠
It's probably no coincidence that the first thing he did
也许不是巧合
was steal the telepathic crown.
塔尼娅说她研究这顶王冠很长时间了
Tanya did say she's been working on the crown for a while.
古鲁德可能知道这是他最好的机会
Grodd probably knew this was his perfect opportunity.
因为我们的装备  这确实是最好的机会
And it was thanks to our tech.
现在古鲁德拿到了王冠
All right, well, now that Grodd has the crown,
如果他使用它的话会发生什么
what's gonna happen when he uses it?
会让他的精神能力增强千倍
It'll amplify his mental abilities a thousand-fold.
这样他就不仅能同时控制几个人的大脑
Instead of just being able to mind control a few people at a time...
他能控制整座城市
He'll be able to control the whole city.
抱歉  打扰了
Forgive me. I'm intruding.
也许没有
Or am I?
我看到他在那边  而你在这边的阴影里
I see him out there and I see you in here in the shadows.
我好奇这是为什么
Why is that, I wonder?
你能责怪我吗
Can you blame me?
你看到他手部的变形了
You saw his hand transform.
看到了  就像《孤岛鲨魂》
Yes, right. "Shark Week!"
不是每天都能见到的景象  但是
Not something you see every day, but no,
我想你的犹豫
I thought your hesitation occurred
之前就出现了  而不是后来
before that moment, not after.
只是很细微的犹豫  但不管怎么说它出现了
It was a slight hesitation, but it was there nonetheless.
那么  你为什么这么想呢
Again, why do you think that is?
我不知道...
I don't know...
不知道  那我就大胆地推测一下
No? Well, perhaps I could be so bold as to offer
或许你害怕的
a suggestion that it is not the hand
不是那只手  而是
of which you were frightened, but rather,
看到那张
it was seeing the face
你爱的男人的脸
of the man that you love.
我不爱沙伊  我们是朋友
I don't love Shay. We're friends.
那好  我们顺便谈谈这个吧
All right, well, let's take a look at that too, shall we?
所以他是你在另一个地球上的朋友
So this is a friend from another Earth,
为了他  你放弃高薪工作
for whom you left a high-paying job
为了他
and for whom you have dedicated
你无时无刻不想着给他帮忙
every waking moment of your life trying to help.
这说不通
It doesn't quite add up.
我不能爱沙伊
I can't love Shay.
他是我地球二上逝世丈夫的二重身
He's my dead husband's doppelganger from Earth-2.
我爱上他的话  那不是太疯狂了吗
How crazy would I have to be to fall in love with him?
与五个不同地球上的同一个女人结婚
No crazier than marrying the same woman
也同样疯狂...
from five different Earths...
我知道
I know.
我很能结婚
I'm very good at marrying people,
但不太能维持婚姻
but not so great at staying married.
但是这一路以来
Along the way, though,
在不同的地球上  遇见不同的二重身
on these countless Earths and countless doppelgangers,
我发现我们在某一方面
I learned there is one thing
总是独一无二的
that makes all of us unique.
如果
And if that
你爱上的是独一无二的那部分
is what you fell in love with, well then,
或许一张脸就不那么重要了
perhaps a face doesn't matter that much.
你错过了一场美丽的日落
You missed a beautiful sunset earlier.
真遗憾
Too bad.
-那是我一天最喜欢的时刻  -我也是
- It's my favorite time of day. - Mine, too.
我差点忘记日落是什么样子了
I almost forgot what one looked like.
你知道鲨鱼是色盲吗
Did you know sharks are colorblind?
变成鲨鱼王的日子里  我的世界黯淡无光
When I was King Shark, my world was dull and gray.
直到我遇见你  一切都变了
And then I met you, and everything changed.
我觉得你在逃避我
I thought you were avoiding me.
过去是  现在不是了
I was, but not anymore.
塔尼娅  你对我失望吗  现在我...
Tanya, are you disappointed in me now that I'm--
一点都不失望
No, not at all.
他们说每个日落都是独特的
They say every sunset is unique.
你觉得是真的吗
Do you think that's true?
是的
Yes, I do.
爸爸  这样不行的
Dad, this is not going to work.
你连试都没试过
You haven't even tried it yet.
听着  我明白
Look, I get it.
我应该朝那沙包发泄不满
I'm supposed to take out my frustrations on that bag
然后不再去想它  但这没那么简单
and somehow get over it, but it's not that easy.
面对让你烦恼的东西吗
To confront what ails you?
的确不简单  非常难
No, it's not. It's hard.
我跨了半个地球才做到
I had to go all the way across the world to do it.
你是说西藏那次吗
Are you talking about Tibet?
我以为你是为了见沃利
I thought you went there to see Wally.
是的  但不全是因为这个
I did, but that's not the only reason I went.
我去那里治愈自己
I went there to heal.
所以你才去那么久的吗
Is that why you were gone for so long?
沃利劝我带着孩子去东方
Wally convinced me to come east with the baby.
他说有助于我舒缓身心
He said it would help me repair my mind,
找回我原本的灵魂
my body, restore this old soul of mine.
所以塞西尔同意后
So with Cecile's blessing,
我就去了
that's what I did.
成功了吗
And did it work?
我能屈能伸  宝贝
I bent, baby girl.
但蝉无法打败我
But Cicada ain't going to break me.
他也无法打败你
Ain't going to break you either.
加油
Come on.
加油  爱瑞丝  让蝉瞧瞧你的厉害
Come on, Iris. Show Cicada what you got.
打败他  爱瑞丝
Break him, Iris.
打败他
Break him!
怎么了
What's happening?
我们毛茸茸的家伙爬上布鲁姆钟楼了
Our fuzzy friend is crawling up the Broome Belfry.
他去塔上干什么
What is it with him and that tower?
因为塔就在市中心...
'Cause it's at the exact epicenter of the city...
是广播的最佳地点
Making it the perfect place to broadcast from.
他要用王冠
He's going to use the crown.
侵入这城市里所有人的思想
And get inside everyone's head in the city.
听好了  人类  你们主人要说话了
Hear your master, Humans.
很快  你们就只会听从我的意志...
Soon, you will only know my will--
我古鲁德的意志
the will of Grodd!
古鲁德需要多久来控制所有人的思想
How long before everyone's under Grodd's mind control?
几分钟  可能更短
A few minutes, maybe less.
我们必须把那王冠从他头上卸下来
We need to dismantle that crown and get it away from him.
我可以试着跟他说话
I can try talking to him.
他总对我比较温柔
He's always had a sweet spot for me.
-太好了  -想得美
- Good. - The hell you will.
不行  冰霜杀手肯定不会同意
Nope, Killer Frost is gonna be a hard sell on that one.
我们对他的大脑控制有免疫  对吗
We're immune to his mind control, right,
因为我们是极速者
because we're speedsters?
没这回事
No.
好吧  闪电侠博物馆里有太多东西都错了
Okay, the Flash Museum just straight up got a lot of stuff wrong.
等等  你还有抗大脑控制的头带吗
Wait, but do you have any extra anti-mind control headsets lying around?
工作室里还有几个
There's a few in the workshop,
但是上次它们不怎么起作用
but it didn't work so well last time.
没错  但是现在有我和诺拉两个人
Yeah, but now there's two of us.
我需要你以最快的速度朝他跑去
I need you to run at him as fast as you can
-但不要让时间倒转  -好的
- without reversing time. - Okay.
-那样能得到他的注意  -那你要做什么
- That'll get his attention. - What are you gonna do?
一个老伎俩
An old trick.
去拿王冠
Get the crown!
爸爸
Dad?
我们动不了了
We can't move.
内心活动缓冲器起作用了
The mental dampeners are working,
但是古鲁德太强了
but Grodd's too strong.
我在尝试黑进王冠里  但是古鲁德在阻止
I'm trying to hack into the crown, but Grodd won't let me.
他会杀了他们的
He's gonna kill them.
如果你能把我变回去就不会
Not if you turn me back.
我能阻止古鲁德
I can stop Grodd.
他无法读我的心
He can't read my mind...at least,
至少在我是鲨鱼的时候他做不到
not when I'm a shark.
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
也许可以  如果我们能加快细胞循环
I mean, if we accelerate the cell cycle,
做些什么来促进细胞
do something that will prompt a return
回到暗物质的形态
to the dark matter cellular form.
对啊  比如振动或者撞击  对吗
Right, right, perhaps a vibration or a jolt, right?
如果足够强烈  是可以的
Yes, if it was strong enough,
但是会有不可更改的后果
but there would be permanent consequences.
如果我们重新让你的超能基因细胞达到饱和
If we re-saturate your meta-genic cells,
它们就没有可能
that will eliminate the possibility
再被转变为人类细胞了
for you to transform them back into human cells.
解药将会对他无效了
He won't be able to use the cure.
沙伊  如果你同意这么做
Shay, if you agree to this,
你将永远无法变回人类
you'll never be human again.
塔尼娅  我能救闪电侠  市民  还有你
Tanya, I can save Flash, the people of this city, you,
补偿我做过的一些糟糕的事情
and make up for some of the horrible things I've done.
我必须这么做
I have to do this.
我害怕失去你
I'm afraid of losing you.
不会的
You won't.
好的  咱这谁能提供振动撞击
Well, is there anyone in this room that can provide a vibrational jolt?
我来搞定
I'm doing it.
我的思维正在壮大
My mind grows.
很快  古鲁德将会控制这个城市
Soon, Grodd will rule this city,
这个世界
this world.
而你
And you...
将会永远消失
gone forever.
鲨鱼王
King Shark?
鲨鱼王要把你干掉
King Shark wants you gone!
哦  不好
Oh, no.
伙计们  鲨鱼王动不了了
Guys, King Shark's not moving.
当鲨鱼被翻个时
When a shark is turned upside down,
会进入紧张性静止状态
it enters tonic immobility.
他处在瘫痪的状态
He's in a state of paralysis.
我们怎么弄醒他
How do we wake him up?
鲨鱼不是有电感接受器官吗
Don't sharks have electroreceptor organs
叫做洛仑兹壶腹
called ampullae of Lorenzini?
被它们用来探测电磁场  对吗
It's how they detect electromagnetic fields, right?
对  它们就是这样定位导航的
Yes, it's how they navigate.
它也能够吸引电流  对吗
And it will also attract electricity, right?
如果我们给他足够强的电流  就能
So if we can get enough electricity to him, we can...
-把他电翻过身  -把他电得翻身朝上
- Electrify his ass back up. - Electrify his ass right up.
-巴里  -我们听见了
- Barry! - Yeah, we heard.
该使另一个老伎俩了
Time for another old trick.
你还好吗
You okay?
-搞定  -太棒了
- Yes! - Yes!
小意思
Nothing to it.
鲨鱼王万岁
Long live the king.
我知道古鲁德几乎把所有人的脑子都搅乱了
I know Grodd almost turned all of our brains into scrambled eggs,
但是那场怪兽之战真是棒呆了
but that Kaiju battle was the stuff of dreams.
说真的  比我在闪电侠博物馆
Seriously, way better than anything
读到的任何东西都棒
I read in The Flash Museum.
现在古鲁德已经被安全关押了
Now that Grodd is safely locked up,
怎样阻止他再逃出来
what's stopping him from getting out again?
他进入了诱导性昏迷
A medically-induced coma,
由凯特琳和天眼会的一名医务人员
one safely administered by Caitlin
共同安全地执行
and the A.R.G.U.S. medical staff.
暴露于王冠之下刺激古鲁德的控制能力
Exposure to the crown kickstarted
进入更强的层次
Grodd's mental abilities into high gear.
他们现在还在增长
They're growing even now.
万幸  我意识到让古鲁德的大脑不再活跃
Fortunately, I realized that if Grodd's brain remains inactive,
他就无法使用他的控制能力
he can't access his mental powers.
加入了全新升级版人工智能阻尼器
Add in newly-enhanced AI power dampeners
更能适配于古鲁德不断增长的能力
that upgrade to keep up with Grodd's power.
不用谢
You're welcome, by the way.
为保城市安全在所不辞
Anything it takes to keep the city safe.
提到保护城市这件事
Speaking of keeping the city safe,
这次还真是多亏了沙伊
we couldn't have done this without Shay.
你们是如何劝说他变回鲨鱼王形态的
How'd you guys convince him to turn back into King Shark?
我们没有劝他
We didn't.
是他自愿的
He volunteered.
他现在永远都不能变回人类了吗
And you can never turn him back into a human?
应该是不能了
I don't think so.
那他将永远是鲨鱼王形态吗
So he's gonna stay King Shark forever?
又是一场正义的胜利
Well, the good guys won once again,
你的脸上可没洋溢着胜利的喜悦
and yet you do not seem like you're really celebrating.
怎么了
Why that is?
今天经历了这么多事
After all that's happened today,
不知道这会不会影响
I just wonder how it will effect--
你们的感情生活吗
Your relationship?
不得不承认  这可是个大问题了
Well, that's a big question, I must admit.
但我相信
But you know what?
你们会解决的  你们两个共克难关
You will figure it out, both of you, together.
真是这样  可就得感谢你了
If so, we'll have you to thank.
-不  不  不  不  -特别是我
- Oh, no, no, no, no. - Me especially.
不  不  不  功劳不在我
No, no, no. I did nothing.
也是  你说的对  我确实帮了点忙
No, you're right, I did help quite a bit.
道理其实很简单
The point here is simply this,
不论他是人还是鲨鱼还是
and that is that whether it's man or shark or...
鲨鱼人
man-shark,
真心亘古不变
the heart wants what the heart wants.
你也得接受这颗真心
And so, you must be open to that.
看来你已经解开了人生的一大难题
Sounds like you've solved life's greatest mystery.
解决难题是我的职责
Well, that's what I do.
如果真是这样
If so,
我希望有一天你也能找到心之所属
I hope one day, you find what you're looking for too--
也许是另一个二重身
maybe in another doppelganger.
当然
Of course.
我就不打搅你们了
I'll leave you to it.
塔尼娅  你很难过的样子
Tanya, you look sad.
为什么
Why?
我们如今找到了彼此
We found each other today,
我们之间的联系却
and now that connection is--
没有断
Still here.
沙伊  你所做的一切
Shay, what you did--
为了你我的选择不会改变  我的爱人
I would do it again for you, my love.
该能屈能伸了
Time to bend.
鲨鱼王大战大猩猩古鲁德
King Shark versus Gorilla Grodd?
逗我呢  我错过了这么场好戏
Are you kidding me? I missed that?
鲨鱼王大战大猩猩古鲁德
但是古鲁德讨厌吃香蕉
你能不能吃点成年人吃的东西
Are you sure you don't want something a bit more grown up?
把你这话收回去
Um, you take that back.
不论多大岁数吃这个零食都是种享受
This snack is a delicacy no matter how old you are.
伙计们
Guys, hey.
我是来...  瑞士鱼软糖
I just--Swedish Fish?
我也爱吃这个
I love those.
我知道今天大家都不容易
look, I know today has been crazy,
我还是想缓和下我们之间的关系
and I just wanted to make sure that we're good,
我知道是古鲁德逼你用震波攻击我
I know Grodd made you blast me in the face
我也知道是我自己活该
but I also know I kinda deserved it--
被冰霜攻击的时候也是我活该
same with being ice blasted.
我不应该把解药当成武器
I shouldn't have used the cure as a weapon
强行注射在鲨鱼王身上
and forced it on King Shark.
我保证不会再发生同样的事
I promise it won't happen again.
接受你的道歉
Apology accepted.
傻瓜
Goober.
我们今天还是有些收获的
And we know something good did come out of today.
超能力者的解药奏效了
We know the meta-human cure works.
可以用解药帮助不止中城以内
And now we can use it to help all of the metas
所有的超能力者了
in Central City and beyond.
先用解药帮助蝉吧
Maybe we start with Cicada.
你说什么
I'm sorry, what?
我知道很荒唐  我只是
I know, I just--
每个人都可能会带来惊喜
people can surprise you.
今天发生的一切让我更加重视这一点
Today definitely reminded me that.
像你经常说的那样  每个人都应该有
And like you've been saying, everybody deserves a choice
选择自己人生道路的机会
to be whoever they want to be--
这也包括我们的敌人在内
that includes our enemies.
我们应该给蝉一份解药
I think we should offer the cure to Cicada.